AMJAD SEYEDI **Graduate Research Assistant**

+98 936 672 1167 @ amjadseyedi@uok.ac.ir

Representation Learning Lab (222), Computer Engineering Department, Engineering Faculty, University of Kurdistan, Sanandaj, Iran



BRIEFLY

As a graduate research assistant at the University of Kurdistan, I work on representation learning with a focus on robustness and generalization. I also lead the Algebraic Machine Learning Team (AML team), a group that explores fundamental methods in unsupervised machine learning and representation theory. I have a Master's degree in Artificial Intelligence from the same university, where I worked with Dr. Parham Moradi and Dr. Fardin Akhlaghian on matrix factorization and low-rank approximation for various applications such as semi-supervised learning, recommendation systems, and multi-label classification. I also have an Associate and a Bachelor's degree in Software Engineering.

RESEARCH INTERESTS

- Machine learning, Representation learning, Linear algebra
- Deep Learning, Self-supervised/Semi-supervised learning
- Generalization, Adversarial training, Robust learning



EXPERIENCE

Thesis Advisor Present

Artificial Intelligence (graduate), UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, SANANDAJ, IRAN, (Sep 2020 - Present)

- > Five students have graduated. I am currently advising six master's students.
- > Topics: representation learning, deep learning, matrix factorization, semi-supervised learning, selfsupervised learning, robust learning, and sparse coding.
- > problems: data representation, data clustering, graph clustering, recommendation systems, link prediction, and feature selection.

Research Assist. Present

Representation Learning, University of Kurdistan, Sanandaj, Iran, (Sep 2019 – Present)

- > Topics: matrix factorization, distributionally robust learning, generalization, and adversarial training
- > applications: image inpainting and recommendation systems.

Teaching Assist. Present

Artificial Intelligence (graduate), UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN,

- > Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Machine Learning (PhD), Fall 2022
- > Statistical Pattern Recognition (Msc), Fall 2018 | Spring 2020 | Spring 2021 | Spring 2022
- > Special Topics in Artificial Intelligence (Msc), Fall 2021
- > lectures: Semi-supervised learning, Modern Machine Learning Paradigms, Nonnegative matrix factorization

Lab Instructor 2019

Computer Lab (undergraduate), UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, SANANDAJ, IRAN, (Fall 2019)

> I had two 14-person classes on computer basics.



EDUCATION

Master 2018

Artificial Intelligence, University of Kurdistan, Sanandaj, Iran, (Sep 2015 - Feb 2018)

- > Thesis title: A Graph-based Semi-Supervised Learning Approach for Multi-Label Classification.
- > Advisors: Dr. Parham Moradi and Dr. Fardin Akhlaghian.
- > Courses: machine learning, statistical pattern recognition, neural networks, advanced artificial intelligence, computer vision, digital image processing, distributed systems, and fuzzy sets & systems.

Bachelor

Sofware Engineering, AMIRKABIR TECHNICAL COLLEGE, ARAK, IRAN, (Jan 2012 - Jun 2014)

> Project title: Manufacturing and Setting up a Video Conferencing Software. 2014

Associate

Computer Software, Tabriz Technical College, Tabriz, Iran, (Jan 2009 – Jun 2011)

2011 > Supplementary courses in computer science and software engineering.

TechSchool | Computer, Taleghani High School, Sanandaj, Iran, (Sep 2005 - Jun 2007)

2007 > A two-year education in basic computer science

> AMJAD SEYEDI 1



Under Review

Deep Asymmetric Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Graph Clustering

A. Hajiveiseh, S. A. Seyedi, and F. Akhlaghian.

Pattern Recognition [Under Review], Mar 2023.

Link Prediction by Adversarial Nonnegative Matrix Factorization

R. Mahmoodi, S. A. Seyedi, F. Akhlaghian, and A. Abdollahpouri.

Knowledge-based Systems [1st Revision], April 2023.

A Bi-level Deep Human Action Representation based on the Sequence of Action Segments

F. Akhlaghian, M. Ramezani, H. Afshoon, and S. A. Seyedi

Neural Computing and Applications [2nd Revision], Feb 2023.

2023 Self-Supervised Semi-Supervised Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Data Clustering

J. Chavoshinejad, S. A. Seyedi, and F. Akhlaghian.

Pattern Recognition, volume 137, 2023, 109282.

Adversarial Elastic Deep Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Matrix Completion

S. A. Seyedi, F. Akhlaghian, A. Lotfi, N. Salahian, and J. Chavoshinejad

Information Sciences, volume 621, 2023, pp. 562-579.

Deep Autoencoder-Like NMF with Contrastive Regularization and Feature Relationship Preservation

N. Salahian, F. Akhlaghian, and S. A. Seyedi, and J. Chavoshinejad

Expert Systems with Applications, volume 214, 2023, 119051.

2020 Asymmetric Semi-Nonnegative Matrix Factorization for Directed Graph Clustering

R. Abdollahi, S. A. Seyedi, and M. R. Noorimehr

IEEE International Conference on Computer and Knowledge Engineering (ICCKE), 2020, pp. 323-328.

Self-Paced Multi-Label Learning with Diversity

S. A. Seyedi, S. S. Ghodsi, F. Akhlaghian Tab, M. Jalili, and P. Moradi Asian Conference on Machine Learning (ACML), 2019, pp. 790–805.

2018 Dynamic Graph-based Label Propagation for Density Peaks Clustering

S. A. Seyedi, A. Lotfi, P. Moradi, and N. N. Qader

Expert Systems with Applications, Volume 115, 2019, pp. 314-328.

2017 A Weakly-Supervised Factorization Method with Dynamic Graph Embedding

S. A. Seyedi, P. Moradi, and F. Akhlaghian Tab

IEEE Artificial Intelligence and Signal Processing Conference (AISP), 2017, pp. 213-218.

A Clustering-based Matrix Factorization Method to Improve the Accuracy of **Recommendation Systems**

Z. Shajarian, S. A. Seyedi, and P. Moradi

IEEE Iranian Conference on Electrical Engineering (ICEE), 2017, pp. 2241-2246.

2016 An Improved Density Peaks Method for Data Clustering

A. Lotfi, S. A. Seyedi, and P. Moradi

IEEE International Conference on Computer and Knowledge Engineering (ICCKE), 2016, pp. 263-268.

COMPUTER SKILLS

Microsoft Windows and Linux (ubuntu, centOS, fedora, and RedHat distributions) Operationg Systems

Word processing & Presentation Offce suites and LTFX

Vector and raster software Adobe Illustrator, CorelDRAW, Inkscape, Adobe Photoshop, and GIMP

Development Tools Pycharm, Jupyter Notebook, Colab, Visual Studio, IntelliJ Idea, and Eclipse

Web design HTML, CSS, ASP.NET, and JavaScript

> AMJAD SEYEDI 2

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

2019 – present
 2015 – present
 2012 – 2015
 2009 – 2015
 4 Python, PyTorch, NumPy, and scikit-learn
 MATLAB, linear algebra and visulaziation
 JAVA, object-oriented software engineeing and web development
 C++ | C#, Software Ebgineering and Web development

2007 – 2009 Basic | Visual Basic, Software Engineering

66 REFERENCES

Fardin Akhlaghian, Associate Professor Department of Computer Engineering UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, SANANDAJ, IRAN

@ f.akhlaghian@uok.ac.ir

+98 918 873 8383

Mahdi Jalili, Associate Professor School of Electrical and Computer Engineering RMIT UNIVERSITY, MELBOURNE, AUSTRALIA

@ mahdi.jalili@rmit.edu.au

+61 399 251 223

Parham Moradi, Associate Professor
Department of Computer Engineering
UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, SANANDAJ, IRAN

p.moradi@uok.ac.ir

+98 912 513 5478

Shahrokh Esmaeili, Associate Professor Department of Mathematics UNIVERSITY OF KURDISTAN, SANANDAJ, IRAN

@ sh.esmaeili@uok.ac.ir

+98 912 425 7584

AMJAD SEYEDI 3